<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ying's Notes</title><link>https://www.caiying.me/</link><description>Recent content on Ying's Notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.caiying.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More Than an API: Why the A2A Protocol is the Cornerstone of the AI Agent Era</title><link>https://www.caiying.me/posts/more-than-api-a2a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.caiying.me/posts/more-than-api-a2a/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are on the verge of an explosion in AI agents. From personal assistants to enterprise automation, countless brilliant &amp;ldquo;digital employees&amp;rdquo; are emerging. Yet, we face a stark reality: these agents live in isolated technical silos, speaking different &amp;ldquo;languages&amp;rdquo; and unable to communicate effectively. We are building a new, digital Tower of Babel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where the Agent2Agent (A2A) protocol comes in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first glance, a technical tutorial for A2A might leave many developers thinking, &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this just a generic async task protocol defined by a few endpoints? I can build that with a standard REST API. What&amp;rsquo;s so special?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cohere's August 2025 Series D+ Round: An Architectural Analysis of Enterprise AI Dominance</title><link>https://www.caiying.me/posts/cohere-series-d-plus-aug-2025/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.caiying.me/posts/cohere-series-d-plus-aug-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>The generative AI sector continues its fervent ascent, and Cohere, on August 14, 2025, underscored its formidable position with an oversubscribed Series D+ funding round of $500 million, securing a post-money valuation of $6.8 billion. This significant capital infusion not only solidifies Cohere&amp;rsquo;s standing as a leading independent AI powerhouse but also sharply defines its &amp;ldquo;enterprise-first, security-first, and cloud-agnostic&amp;rdquo; business logic and strategic boundaries. For senior AI technical developers and researchers, this round is a testament to Cohere&amp;rsquo;s distinct architectural philosophy in a highly competitive landscape.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perplexity Comet: An Agentic AI Browser for the Cognition Era</title><link>https://www.caiying.me/posts/perplexity-comet-agentic-ai-browser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.caiying.me/posts/perplexity-comet-agentic-ai-browser/</guid><description>&lt;p>Perplexity Comet, launched in July 2025, represents a significant paradigm shift in web interaction, aiming to transform the browser from a passive navigation tool into an active, cognitive partner capable of executing complex, multi-step tasks. Positioned within a rapidly expanding AI browser market, projected to reach $76.8 billion by 2034, Comet challenges the dominance of traditional browsers like Google Chrome, which currently holds a 68% market share.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core vision behind Comet is to evolve from an &amp;ldquo;answer engine&amp;rdquo; to an &amp;ldquo;action engine,&amp;rdquo; seamlessly integrating AI into the user&amp;rsquo;s workflow to amplify intelligence and reduce friction. This strategic pivot is a response to the commoditization of pure &amp;ldquo;answer engines&amp;rdquo; as major players like Google and OpenAI integrate real-time search into their foundational models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep Dive into fal.ai's Series C Funding: A Triumph of Technical Acumen and Market Foresight</title><link>https://www.caiying.me/posts/fal-ai-series-c-funding-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.caiying.me/posts/fal-ai-series-c-funding-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the current burgeoning landscape of generative AI, the infrastructure layer is proving its unparalleled value as the &amp;ldquo;picks and shovels&amp;rdquo; provider. fal.ai, a platform dedicated to generative media infrastructure (images, video, and audio), recently closed a $125 million Series C funding round, pushing its valuation to an impressive $1.5 billion. This significant capital injection is not merely a financial milestone; it serves as a robust validation of fal.ai&amp;rsquo;s core technological trajectory, strategic market positioning, and exceptional team execution. This article offers an in-depth analysis of the underlying logic behind fal.ai&amp;rsquo;s Series C success and the compelling reasons why top-tier investors have so eagerly committed.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>